Hello, Namaskar friends, welcome to you.
Today we are talking about how we
can remove our PAN card from IRDA online from home.
We are going to give you complete information about it.
We can say how we
can get NOC which is going to be useful for us to
join any other company.
So we are going to tell you all these things in it that
how can you
deactivate your code,
how can
you deactivate your insurance code and
you can join any other company. So let's
talk about this video today that
how will you remove your PAN from IRDA or
how
can you deactivate your insurance code and
how can you get NOC.
So let's start today's video. So
friends, first of all we will go to
googleclassroom.com p iib.gov.in.
After clicking on it, you will get
to see an interface like this,
but you have to scroll it up a little
and here you will see  You will
get Click Here Self Deactivation
Portal Invoice Self Deactivation Portal,
so you have to click here, as soon as you
click here, you will
see this type of interface here,
first of all you will see your PAN number above, so
you have to fill your PAN number here,
then you will get your mobile number, you have to
enter the mobile number here, after that
you have got this code, you have to
enter this code here, after entering it you
will submit from here and
after submitting it will take you to the next page,
so friends, we have filled all our details, filled the
PAN number, filled the mobile number and filled the
captcha code and submitted it
and the OTP has been generated,
now we will enter our OTP in it, so
let us enter our OTP in it, so
we are entering our OTP in it right now,
after entering the OTP, we submitted it from here, so
after submitting,
you will get to see your PAN number, your company, whatever it is,
and here
you will see it in the last, click here
to deactivate, so now we
click here  If we do this, as soon as we
click on it, you can see that a
message has come here that your request for
deactivation has been sent to your representative
insurance company insurance intermediary,
you will get a notification, that is, now
within 30 days we will get a notification
and this code of ours will be deactivated,
hope you liked this video, if you liked it then do
not forget to like and share it.